[{
        "question": "Lal Ded (Lalla Yogeshwari) was a practitioner of which of the following traditions?",
        "option1": "Tibetan Buddhism",
        "option2": "Kashmir Shaivism",
        "option3": "Sri Sampradaya",
        "option4": "Smartism",
        "answer": "Kashmir Shaivism"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following features of Indian temples resembles pylons of the Egyptian temples?",
        "option1": "Lat",
        "option2": "Vimana",
        "option3": "Gopura",
        "option4": "Shikhara",
        "answer": "Gopura"
    },
    {
        "question": "Hanukkh, the festival of light is associated with which one of the following religions? ",
        "option1": "Hindu",
        "option2": "Jewish",
        "option3": "Muslim",
        "option4": "Christian",
        "answer": "Jewish"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which among the following temples of India is known as Black Pagoda? ",
        "option1": "Sun Temple, Konark",
        "option2": "Brihadeeswara Temple, Tanjore",
        "option3": "Lord Jagannath Temple, Puri",
        "option4": "Meenakshi Temple, Madurai",
        "answer": "Sun Temple, Konark"
    },
    {
        "question": "The famous “Ganga Sagar Mela”, an annual fair is held in which state of India?",
        "option1": "Bihar",
        "option2": "Uttar Pradesh",
        "option3": "Jharkhand",
        "option4": "West Bengal",
        "answer": "West Bengal"
    },
    {
        "question": "The festival Baisakhi or Vaisakhi is commemorates which among the following important event of Sikh History?",
        "option1": "Establishment of Akal Takht",
        "option2": "Establishment of Khalasa Panth",
        "option3": "Establishment of Guru Granth Sahib as permanent guru of Sikhs",
        "option4": "Foundation of Harmandir Sahib (Golden Temple) in Amritsar",
        "answer": "Establishment of Khalasa Panth"
    },
    {
        "question": "Veda which is partly in prose and partly in verses is ___ ?",
        "option1": "Rigveda",
        "option2": "Samaveda",
        "option3": "Yajurveda",
        "option4": "Atharvaveda",
        "answer": "Yajurveda"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following Sikh Guru compiled the Adi Granth?",
        "option1": "Guru Nanak",
        "option2": "Guru Govind Singh",
        "option3": "Guru Arjan Dev",
        "option4": "Guru Har Rai",
        "answer": "Guru Arjan Dev"
    },
    {
        "question": "Flowers, leaves and plants were depicted first time in the paintings of which period?",
        "option1": "Mughal Sultanat",
        "option2": "Gupta Period",
        "option3": "Maurya Period",
        "option4": "Delhi Sultanat",
        "answer": "Delhi Sultanat"
    },
    {
        "question": "Miniature painting was developed in which part of India?",
        "option1": "Northern India",
        "option2": "North-West India",
        "option3": "Eastern India",
        "option4": "North-East India",
        "answer": "Eastern India"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Progressive Artists Group in Bombay in 1948 was developed under _______",
        "option1": "K.C.S Paniker",
        "option2": "Francis Newton Souza",
        "option3": "S.H. Raza",
        "option4": "S.K. Bakre",
        "answer": "Francis Newton Souza"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which Buddhist text describes the existence of painted figures in many royal buildings?",
        "option1": "Vinayapitaka",
        "option2": "Sut Pitaka",
        "option3": "Abhidhamma Pitaka",
        "option4": "None of the above",
        "answer": "Vinayapitaka"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who was the author of the book Kitab-i-Yamini?",
        "option1": "Abul Fazl",
        "option2": "Abu Nasr Utbi",
        "option3": "Amir Khusro",
        "option4": "Firdausi",
        "answer": "Abu Nasr Utbi"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who wrote Tughlaqnama?",
        "option1": "Abu Nasr Utbi",
        "option2": "Abul Fazl",
        "option3": "Amir Khusrau",
        "option4": "Hasan Nizami",
        "answer": "Amir Khusrau"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who brought the famous Persian painter named Khwaja Abdus Samad to India?",
        "option1": "Humayun",
        "option2": "Muhammad Bin Tughlaq",
        "option3": "Akbar",
        "option4": "Alauddin Khilji",
        "answer": "Humayun"
    }
]